Finding Aid for College of Engineering (University of Michigan) records 1860-2010
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Student and Alumni Records, 1895-1991
  - Alumni
    - Class of 1904
      - General Correspondence (), 1904-1961; bulk 1924-1929 (Box 77)
      - Reunions, 1914-1941; 6 folders (Box 77)
      - Reunions, 1934-1965; 15 folders (Box 78)
    - Class Officers Council, 1927-1957 (Box 78)
    - Engineering College Alumni Conference, 1941 (Box 78)
    - Michigan Club of Philadelphia, 1938-1948 (Box 78)
  - Students
    - Camp Davis Diary of Peter C. Hammelef, 1915 (Box 78)
    - "Campus Development" by George J. Lutz, 1935 (Box 78)
    - Class of 1917 Secretary's Book, 1913-1914 (Box 78)
    - Course Evaluations, 1982-1983; 10 folders (Box 79)
    - Great Books Program, 1967-1968 (Box 80)
    - Honor System, 1916-1951 (Box 80)
    - Honors Luncheon, 1972-1987; 16 folders (Box 80)
    - Honors Luncheon, 1988-1989; 2 folders (Box 81)
    - Program Advising, 1965-1977; 3 volumes (Box 81)
    - Situational Study: Engineering Ethics Questions, undated (Box 81)
    - Student Notebook of Alfred Finney-Dynamo Electric Machinery, 1902-1903 (Box 81)
    - Student Organizations-General Correspondence, 1985-1991 (Box 81)
    - Student Publications
      - The Anvil, 1985-1986; 2 folders (Box 81)
      - Engineering College Magazine Association (ECMA), 1986-1989 (Box 81)
      - Engineering Student Publications, 1986-1990 (Box 81)
        (re Anvil and Technic
      - Michigan Technic
        - Articles of Management, 1939; 1983 (Box 81)
        - Awards, 1938-1976 (Box 81)
        - Cooley Writing Contest, circa 1985-1987 (Box 81)
        - Correspondence, 1944-1982 (Box 82)
        - High School Distribution, 1939-1957 (Box 82)
        - Ledgers, 1958-1963 (Box 82)
      - Student Newsletters, 1986-1987 (Box 82)
- Administrative Staff Records, 1966-1982
  The Administrative Staff Records series (1966-1982) consists of one linear foot of Development Office records regarding two fund-raising campaigns: the 55 Million Campaign and the Capital Campaign. The 55 Million Campaign was a university-wide effort; files here reflect the College of Engineering's contacts with various corporations. The Capital Campaign, which ran from 1972-1979, was limited to the College of Engineering, and served as a model for the university-wide Capital Campaign which began in 1980. Materials here include internal reports, pamphlets, donor lists, memos, and some correspondence.
  - Development Office
    - 55 Million Campaign, 1966-1971
      - General Information (Box 36)
      - Consumers Power (Box 36)
      - General Electric (Box 36)
      - Gibbs (Box 36)
      - 3 M Company (Box 36)
      - U.S. Steel (Box 36)
      - Westinghouse (Box 36)
    - Capital Campaign, 1973-1982
      - General Information (Box 36)
      - Projects (Box 36)
      - Proposals (Box 36)
      - Publications (Box 36)
      - Individual Donors
        - Donor Lists and Information, 1977-1978 (Box 36)
        - Mailing Kit, 1978 (Box 36)
        - Unpaid Donors, 1982 (Box 36)
      - Corporate Donors
        - Corporate Rationale, 1974 (Box 36)
        - Corporations Committee, 1974-1975 (Box 36)
        - Potential Donors (Corporate), 1974 (Box 36)
        - Review of Corporate Activity, 1977-1978 (Box 36)
      - Campaign Completion, 1976-1978 (Box 36)
      - Campaign Final Report, 1979; 2 folders (Box 36)
- College Administration, 1902-1989
  College Administration is a catch-all series of files created by administrative staff at the College of Engineering. Most of these records date from the years 1968 to 1989, although some were created as early as 1902. The series should be considered in tandem with previous accessions, as there is some overlap in terms of both chronology and content. The series is divided into five subseries: Older Administrative Files [pre-1960]; Departmental Files; Financial Records; Topical Files; and Awards.
  - Older Administrative Files (pre-1960)
    The Older Administrative Files [pre-1960] (1.75 linear feet) contain correspondence, memoranda, reports and meeting minutes dating from 1902 to 1962. Of particular interest are detailed enrollment statistics from the 1940s and 1950s, records concerning curriculum development, and files on cooperative programs between the College and the military during both world wars.
    - Architecture Students, 1931-1939 (Box 62)
    - Army Stores Course, 1917-1922 (Box 62)
    - Business Administration Combined Program, 1934-1941 (Box 62)
    - Civil Engineering Enrollments 1890-1935 compiled, 1935
      - Report, 1936 (Box 62)
    - Engineering Council, undated (Box 62)
    - English Curriculum, 1924-1942 (Box 62)
    - Enrollment Statistics, 1947-1953; 7 volumes (Box 62)
    - Enrollment Statistics, 1954-1955; 2 volumes (Box 63)
    - "The Establishment of Military Training and the ROTC at UM", undated (Box 63)
    - Faculty Action, 1936-1951 (Box 63)
    - Ford Motor Company, 1959 (Box 63)
    - Geodesy and Surveying, 1921-1924 (Box 63)
    - Grading Procedures, 1948-1953 (Box 63)
    - Graduate Lists, 1904-1918 (Box 63)
    - Highway Engineering and Transportation, 1919-1931 (Box 63)
    - Honors Course, 1920-1923 (Box 63)
    - Mathematics, 1928-1942 (Box 63)
    - Mechanical Engineering, 1940-1952 (Box 63)
    - Meter Short Course, 1923-1933 (Box 63)
    - Municipal Engineering, 1937-1938 (Box 63)
    - Naval ROTC Correspondence, 1939-1941 (Box 63)
    - Navy V-12 Course Equivalents, circa 1945 (Box 63)
    - Navy V-12 Program, 1943-1945 (Box 63)
    - Power Plant Operating Expenses, 1937-1938 (Box 63)
    - Salary Information, 1959-1960 (Box 63)
    - Scholastic Standing Committee, 1936-1949 (Box 63)
    - Science Engineering, 1959-1960 (Box 63)
    - Short Courses, 1956 (Box 63)
    - Statistics and Studies, 1902-1962 (Box 63)
    - Veterans Refresher Course, 1945 (Box 84)
      [CR RESTRICTED until Jan. 1, 2045 ]
  - Departmental Files
    The Departmental Files subseries (3.5 linear feet) dates from 1965 to 1985 and contains memoranda, reports and some correspondence. The records were received, and are filed, in two sections: a "General" alphabetical file and "Departmental Reviews". The latter were carried out internally and often contain frank assessments of the strengths, weaknesses and future plans of the department under review. For several departments, reviews have been conducted in conjunction with chairman searches. For a more detailed description of the departmental review process, see the file "Departmental Reviews - Policy and Schedule" [box 66].
    - General
      - Aerospace Memoranda and Reports, 1968-1980 (Box 84)
      - Applied Mechanics and Engineering Science Correspondence, 1971-1977 (Box 63)
      - Applied Physics, 1984-1985 (Box 63)
      - Artificial Intelligence Proposal, 1985 (Box 63)
      - Atmospheric and Oceanic Science, 1968-1982; 2 folders (Box 63)
      - Bioengineering Memoranda, 1968-1979 (Box 63)
      - Chemical Engineering Memoranda, 1973-1979; 2 folders (Box 63)
      - Civil Engineering Memoranda and Reports, 1974-1980; 2 folders (Box 63)
      - Computer, Information and Control Engineering (CICE), 1969-1980 (Box 84)
        - General, 1970-1980 (Box 64)
        - Program Reviews, 1969-1977 (Box 64)
      - Electrical and Computer Engineering, 1978-1980
        - Memoranda, 1974-1977 (Box 64)
      - General Planning Documents, 1980-1981 (Box 64)
      - Humanities Program
        - Marwil Case, 1978-1980; 2 folders (Box 84)
        - Memoranda, 1973-1978 (Box 64)
      - Industrial and Operations Engineering Memoranda, 1972-1980 (Box 84)
      - Materials and Metallurgical Engineering Memoranda, 1971-1978 (Box 64)
      - Mechanical Engineering and Applied Mechanics, 1978-1980 (Box 84)
      - Mechanical Engineering Memoranda and Reports, 1971-1977 (Box 64)
      - Naval Architecture and Marine Engineering
        - Memoranda, 1973-1980; 2 folders (Box 84)
        - Memoranda and Reports, 1969-1971 (Box 64)
        - Review Material, 1970-1971 (Box 64)
      - Nuclear Engineering Memoranda, 1971-1980
        - 1971-1980 (Box 64)
        - 1973-1980 (Box 84)
      - Personnel Matters, 1981-1982 (Box 84)
      - Space Allocations, 1981 (Box 64)
    - Departmental Reviews
      - Aerospace Engineering, 1973; 1978; 2 folders (Box 64)
      - Applied Mechanics and Engineering Science, 1976-1978 (Box 64)
      - Atmospheric and Oceanic Science, 1973-1980; 3 folders (Box 64)
      - Atmospheric and Oceanic Science, 1984-1985; 2 folders (Box 65)
      - Bioengineering Review Committees, 1969-1979 (Box 65)
      - Chemical and Metallurgical Engineering Split, 1969 (Box 65)
      - Chemical Engineering, 1969-1982
        - Review committee, 1977-1982; 3 folders (Box 65)
        - Chairman Search, 1969-1972; 2 folders (Box 84)
        - Chairman Search, 1976-1977; 2 folders (Box 85)
      - Civil Engineering, 1966-1981; 3 folders (Box 65)
      - Computer, Information and Control Engineering (CICE), 1975-1977; 2 folders (Box 65)
      - Electrical and Computer Engineering, 1972-1980
        - General, 1972-1980; 3 folders (Box 65)
        - Chairman Search, 1974-1975 (Box 85)
      - Engineering Mechanics, 1965-1971 (Box 65)
      - Humanities
        - General
          - 1970-1981 (Box 65)
          - 1970-1981 (Box 85)
        - Chairman Search, 1975 (Box 85)
      - Industrial and Operations Engineering, 1964-1980
        - Chairman Search, 1973-1977 (Box 85)
      - Manufacturing Engineering, 1979-1981 (Box 66)
      - Materials and Metallurgical Engineering, 1973-1978; 2 folders
        - 1973-1978 (Box 66)
        - 1973-1978 (Box 85)
      - Mechanical Engineering (includes chairman search), 1974 (Box 85)
      - Meteorology and Oceanography, 1967-1971 (Box 66)
      - Naval Architecture and Marine Engineering, 1962-1981; 6 folders
        - General, 1962-1981; 3 folders (Box 66)
        - Chairman Search, 1973 (Box 84)
        - Chairman Search, 1981; 2 folders (Box 85)
      - Nuclear Engineering, 1965-1979 (Box 66)
      - Office for the Study of Automotive Transportation, 1980-1981 (Box 66)
      - Policy and Schedule, circa 1968 (Box 66)
      - Power Systems Program Review Report, 1978 (Box 66)
  - Financial Records
    The Financial Records (1 linear foot) contain College budgets from 1937 to 1979 as well as records from the Capital Campaign of the 1970s, which played an important role in helping finance construction on North Campus. For related information, see also the more general "Budget Information" file in box 67.
    - Budgets, 1937-1979; 8 volumes; 1 folders
      - 1937-1971 (Box 66)
      - 1972-1979, 2 volumes (Box 85)
    - Capital Campaign
      - Closed Circuit Television, 1971-1977 (Box 67)
      - Fleming, R.W., 1974 (Box 67)
      - H.H. Dow Building, 1975-1980 (Box 67)
      - Joint Capital Outlay Subcommittee, 1974-1975 (Box 67)
      - Naming Gift Opportunities, 1975-1978 (Box 67)
      - North Campus Master Plan, 1974-1977 (Box 67)
      - Planning Committee, 1972-1976 (Box 67)
      - Planning Committee Meeting Minutes, 1976-1977 (Box 67)
      - State of Michigan, 1976-1977 (Box 67)
      - Student Centers, 1974-1978 (Box 67)
  - Topical Files
    Topical Files (3.5 linear feet) is a very diverse subseries which consists of correspondence, memoranda, and reports. The subseries covers the years 1930 to 1985, although most files date from the late 1960s to the mid-1980s. The Topical Files contain Annual Reports; a 1980 External Review; faculty records, including Faculty Meeting Minutes from 1968 to 1983; and Sabbatical Leave Reports from the early 1980s.
    - Admissions Data Base, 1975 (Box 67)
    - Agricultural Aviation, 1977 (Box 67)
    - Annual Reports, 1974-1988; 7 folders (Box 67)
    - Big Ten Deans (of Engineering), 1978-1981 (Box 67)
    - Bioengineering, 1962-1965
      - Program, 1969-1979; undated; 2 folders (Box 67)
    - Board of Admissions, 1974 (Box 67)
    - Budget Information, 1975-1981; 5 folders (Box 67)
    - Building Maintenance, 1972-1976 (Box 67)
    - Building Usage, 1975-1977 (Box 67)
    - Calcusearch, Inc., 1974-1977 (Box 68)
    - Civil Engineering: Future of Environmental Programs, 1970 (Box 68)
    - "The College of Engineering: Status and Future", 1981 (Box 68)
    - Community Colleges, 1974-1976 (Box 68)
    - Computer Facilities and Services, 1978-1981 (Box 68)
    - Computer Purchase, 1983 (Box 68)
    - Department Planning, 1972-1973 (Box 68)
    - Detroit Nuclear Study Club (G. Knoll's lecture notes), 1971 (Box 68)
    - Development Campaign Job Descriptions, 1973 (Box 68)
    - Dow Building Planning Committee, 1980 (Box 68)
    - Electrical and Computer Engineering, 1970-1973
      - Computer Graphics Program, 1972-1980; 2 folders (Box 68)
      - Farris, H.W. Correspondence, 1968-1972 (Box 68)
      - Kan Chen Advisory Committee, 1972 (Box 68)
    - Engineering Council, 1964-1977 (Box 68)
    - Evaluation and Planning Project, 1976-1978 (Box 68)
    - Executive Committee Correspondence, 1972-1973 (Box 68)
    - External Review, 1980 (Box 68)
    - Faculty
      - Consulting Reports, 1970 (Box 68)
      - Handbook Proposal, 1961 (Box 68)
      - Meeting Minutes, 1968-1983; 5 folders (Box 69)
      - Policies, 1963-1964 (Box 69)
      - Rules, 1968-1975; 2 folders (Box 69)
      - Salaries, 1978-1980; 2 folders (Box 85)
    - "Game Plan" (draft), circa 1968 (Box 69)
    - Graduate Student Recruitment, 1977 (Box 69)
    - Hellwarth, A.R., 1970-1973 (Box 69)
    - High Schools, 1962-1968 (Box 69)
    - Kanpur Indo-American Program, 1962-1968 (Box 69)
    - Kikuchi, Chihiro, 1966-1969 (Box 69)
    - Knoll and Kikuchi N.S.F. Research Grant, 1966-1968 (Box 69)
    - Knoll, Professor Glenn-Research Projects, 1965-1968 (Box 69)
    - Leadership Conference, 1974 (Box 69)
    - Materials and Metallurgy Co-op Program, 1975-1976 (Box 69)
    - Minutes of Department Chairman Meetings, 1981 (Box 69)
    - Mortimer G. Cooley Fund Correspondence (sample), 1946-1954 (Box 69)
    - NASA Project, 1969-1970 (Box 69)
    - National Executive Committee, 1973-1974 (Box 70)
    - Navy Cooperative Program, 1980-1981 (Box 70)
    - New Faculty, 1978-1980 (Box 70)
    - Office for the Study of Automotive Transportation (OSAT), 1980-1981 (Box 70)
    - Ph.D. Review Committee, 1978 (Box 70)
    - Plans and Projections, 1970-1973 (Box 70)
    - "Plans for Developing an Engineering and Technology Center on the North Campus", 1966 (Box 70)
    - Program Advisers, 1973; 1980-1981 (Box 70)
    - Ranking Statistics, 1962-1963 (Box 70)
    - Research Policy, 1974-1979 (Box 70)
    - Rest Room Data, undated (Box 70)
    - Robotics, 1981 (Box 70)
    - Rules of the Faculty, 1968 (Box 70)
    - Sabbatical Leave Reports, 1981-1985; 3 folders (Box 70)
    - Space Allocation, 1976-1981; 2 folders (Box 70)
    - Student Data, 1976-1977 (Box 70)
    - Summaries of Staff Research, 1930 (Box 70)
    - Survey Tower, 1975-1976 (Box 70)
    - Tau Beta Pi, 1978-1981 (Box 70)
    - Undergraduate Programs, 1973-1978 (Box 70)
  - Awards, 1951-1995
    The Awards subseries spans the periods 1951-1981 and 1972-1995; major awards for faculty and students are filed alphabetically in tow separate listings. Information in the records includes lists of recipients, nomination letters, and descriptions of awards criteria.
    - Awards, 1951-1981
      - Amoco Outstanding Teaching Award, 1981-1987 (Box 71)
      - Attwood (Stephen S.) Award, 1970-1989; 14 folders (Box 71)
      - Benton Fellowship, 1983-1988 (Box 71)
      - Benton Professorship, 1983 (Box 71)
      - Class of '31 Scholarship, 1986 (Box 71)
      - Class of 1938E Award, 1960-1988 (Box 71)
      - Distinguished
        - Alumni Award, 1969-1985 (Box 71)
        - Faculty Achievement Award, 1976-1987; 2 folders (Box 71)
        - Professional Achievement Award, 1968-1987 (Box 71)
        - Professorship, 1961-1977 (Box 71)
        - Service Awards, 1963-1973 (Box 71)
        - Teaching Fellow Award, 1968-1974 (Box 71)
        - Undergraduate Teaching Award, 1965-1968 (Box 71)
      - Faculty Recognition Award, 1981-1986 (Box 71)
      - Honorary Degrees, 1951-1977; 2 folders (Box 72)
      - King/Chavez/Parks Scholars, 1986-1989; 2 folders (Box 72)
      - Kucher (Andrew A.) Award, 1960-1976 (Box 72)
      - Michigan Association of Governing Board (MAGB), 1988-1989; 2 folders (Box 72)
      - Outstanding Alumni Achievement Award, 1958-1989 (Box 72)
      - Outstanding Teaching Assistant Award, 1981-1987 (Box 72)
      - Rackham One Term Dissertation Fellowships, 1988 (Box 72)
      - Research Excellence Award, 1980-1989; 8 folders (Box 72)
      - Rockwell International, 1989 (Box 72)
      - Singleton Award for Outstanding Sophomore Student, 1976 (Box 72)
      - Teaching Excellence Award, 1980-1985; 6 folders (Box 72)
      - Teaching Excellence Award, 1986-1989; 4 folders (Box 73)
      - White (Edward H. II) Fellowship Award, 1967-1976 (Box 73)
    - Awards, 1972-1995
      - Acheson, Howard A. Memorial Scholarship, 1991 (Box 88)
      - Alumnae in Residence Award, 1990 (Box 88)
      - Alumni Award, 1976 (Box 88)
      - Anderson Consulting Scholarship, 1990-1991 (Box 88)
      - American Society for Engineering Education (ASEE) Award, 1992 (Box 88)
      - ASM Materials Science Division Research Award, 1990 (Box 88)
      - Athena Award, 1972-1991 (Box 88)
      - Atwood, Stephen S. Award
        - 1991, 2 folders (Box 88)
        - 1992-1993 (Box 88)
      - Australia Prize, 1996 (Box 88)
      - Bailey, Steele and Mildred Award, 1990 (Box 88)
      - Black Engineer of the Year Award, 1993 (Box 88)
      - Bower Award, 1992-1994 (Box 88)
      - Carlson, Chester Award, 1992 (Box 88)
      - Committee on Institutional Cooperation (CIC) Leadership Program, 1991 (Box 88)
      - Class of 1938E Award
        - 1989-1991, 2 folders (Box 88)
        - 1993-1994 (Box 88)
      - College Service Excellence Award, 1991 (Box 88)
      - Distinguished Research Professor Award, 1990 (Box 88)
      - Engineering Society of Detroit Award, 1994-1995 (Box 88)
      - Fermi, Enrico Award, 1996 (Box 88)
      - General Electric Outstanding Young Student Award, 1991 (Box 88)
      - Goddard-Power, Sarah Award, 1992-1993 (Box 88)
      - Goebel Class Award, 1992-1993 (Box 88)
      - Goodwin, Clifton S. Prize, 1990-1991 (Box 88)
      - Harden, Elaine Award, 1991 (Box 88)
      - Henry Ford II Award, 1990-1991 (Box 88)
      - Honorary Doctor of Science Degree, 1990 (Box 88)
      - Honors and Awards Committee, 1990-1994 (Box 88)
      - Humbolt Research Award, 1994 (Box 88)
      - Jones, Reginald H. Distinguished Service Award, 1991 (Box 89)
      - Katz Donald L. Lectureship, 1988-1990 (Box 89)
      - Keck Foundation Award, 1993-1994 (Box 89)
      - Lamme Award, 1988-1995 (Box 89)
      - Marlowe, Donald E. Award, 1992 (Box 89)
      - McGraw, Curtis Award, 1992 (Box 89)
      - Michigan Agenda for Women Award, 1994-1995 (Box 89)
      - Meriam/Wiley Distinguished Author Award, 1991-1992 (Box 89)
      - Michigan Association of Governing Board (MAGB) Award, 1990-1995 (Box 89)
      - Michigan Society of Fellows, 1991 (Box 89)
      - National Academy of Engineering (NAE) Awards, 1990-1995 (Box 89)
      - National Academy of Sciences Appointment, 1991 (Box 89)
      - National Medal of Technology, 1992 (Box 89)
      - National Science Foundation (NSF) Incentive for Excellence Prize, 1991 (Box 89)
      - Neubacher, Jim Award, 1991 (Box 89)
      - Outstanding Alumni Achievement Award, 1990-1994 (Box 89)
      - Palladium Medal, 1991 (Box 89)
      - Pecora, William T. Award, 1990-1991 (Box 89)
      - Pew Scholars, 1991 (Box 89)
      - Research Excellence Award
        - 1990-1991 (Box 89)
        - 1992, 3 folders (Box 89)
        - 1993-1994, 2 folders (Box 89)
      - Roe, Ralph Coates Award, 1992 (Box 89)
      - Russell, Henry Lecturer
        - 1954-1995(scattered) (Box 89)
      - Schlumberger Collegiate Merit Award, 1990-1991 (Box 89)
      - Schlumberger Graduate Fellowship, 1990-1991 (Box 89)
      - Senior Research Award, 1992 (Box 90)
      - Service Excellence Award
        - 1991-1992 (Box 90)
        - 1993-1994 (Box 90)
      - Smith, Goff Award, 1987-1993 (Box 90)
      - State of Michigan Teaching Excellence Award, 1991 (Box 90)
      - Tau Beta Pi Award Winners (Box 90)
      - Teaching Excellence Award
        - 1990 (Box 90)
        - 1991, 2 folders (Box 90)
        - 1992, 2 folders (Box 90)
        - 1993-1994 (Box 90)
      - Teetor, Ralph R., 1991-1995 (Box 90)
      - Thurnau Professorship Award
        - 1991-1992 (Box 90)
        - 1993-1994 (Box 90)
      - Tyler Prize, 1988 (Box 90)
      - University Awards, 1966-1980 (scattered) (Box 90)
      - University Governance Award, 1992 (Box 90)
      - University Professorship, 1992 (Box 90)
      - University Research Scientist Award, 1988 (Box 90)
      - University Research Scientist Lectureship, 1990 (Box 90)
      - Vulcan Award, 1988 (Box 90)
      - Waterman, Alan T. Award, 1991 (Box 90)
      - Women of Color Award, 1990 (Box 90)
- Visual Materials, circa 1900-1975
  The series of Visual Materials (1.5 linear feet) consists of photographs which portray the activities, facilities, faculty, and alumni of the College of Engineering and consist generally of black and white positive prints. This series contains the photographs received in each of the accessions of records from the College of Engineering.
  The photographs date from the late nineteenth century to 1996, and include portraits of faculty and students; interiors and exteriors of buildings; laboratory scenes from the 1910s and 1920s; and aerial views of North Campus. The "Miscellaneous Buildings and Faculty" binder contains some of the earliest photographs of Engineering buildings and laboratories, and some unusual pictures of faculty, such as a group inspecting the new 1932 Hudson Essex automobile. The oversize photographs in box 83 consist of class composite portraits from the nineteenth century; portraits of prominent alumni dating from the 1910s and 1920s; and a group picture taken at Camp Davis in 1885. For portraits of former faculty, the researcher should also examine the Photographic Rosters from the years 1960-1979 located in the Faculty Records series (Box 35).
  The oversize photographs in box 83, 94 and two outsize folders consist of class composite portraits from the 1860s to the 1930s (with some missing years); portraits of prominent alumni dating from the 1910s and 1920s; and a group picture taken at Camp Davis in 1885.
  The videotape in the Visual Materials series was made in 1974, and is the result of a National Closed-Circuit Telecast fundraising program.
  - Photographs
    - Aerospace Engineering, Department of
      - Aeronautical Research Center (proposed building), 1948; black and white positive prints (Box 50)
      - Michigan Aviation Hall of Fame event,C. Vest receiving plaque, 1988; 1 prints color (Box 50)
    - Chrysler Center for Continuing Engineering Education, dedication of, undated; black and white positive prints (Box 50)
    - Chrysler Institute of Engineering, Junior Engineers, Classes of, 1936-1938; 1 volumes black and white (Box 50)
    - Class of 1918 Reunions, 1938; 1953; 1958; black and white positive prints (Box 50)
    - Coal Mining (Robert Gage Coal Co., Mine no. 10, Unionville), 1935-1937; black and white positive prints (Box 50)
    - Engineering Building (Central Campus), 1959; 1962 undated; black and white positive prints (Box 50)
    - Experimental Research in Electronic Submission (EXPRES) Project, 1988 undated; color positive prints, color slides, and color negatives (Box 50)
    - Faculty and Deans, undated; black and white positive prints (Box 50)
      (see also Faculty Photographic Rosters in Box 35)
    - Honors Convocation, 1964; 1969; black and white positive prints (Box 50)